Guide to the Annette Sara Cunningham Papers on the Irish Export Board AIA.071
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Annette Sara Cunningham Papers on the Irish Export Board
1977-1986
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Cunningham, Annette Sara
AIA.071
0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 2 folders in shared oversize flat boxes
Anne Sara Cunnginham worked as the Press and Information Officer in North America for the Irish Export Board during the 1970s and 1980s. The Irish Export Board (Córas Tráchtala) was an economic development agency that emphasized marketing Irish-owned businesses and Irish products to global audiences. This collection contains photographs, catalogs, brochures, advertisements, printed ephemera, press releases, and newspaper articles documenting the Board's activities in North America, with specific fashion or home furnishing campaigns revealing the strategies and attempts to create an identity for Irish business that extended beyond agrarian stereotypes.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
Anne Sara Cunnginham worked as the Press and Information Officer in North America for the Irish Export Board during the 1970s and 1980s. The Irish Export Board (Córas Tráchtala) was an economic development agency that emphasized marketing Irish-owned businesses and Irish products to global audiences. The Board was founded in 1959 and later merged with a private company. Enterprise Ireland, a government organization devoted to the growth and development of Irish businesses in global markets, superseded the Irish Export Board and other similar organizations. The Irish Export Board often emphasized fashion, home furnishings, and other consumer products, with notable campaigns focusing on Irish whiskey, a series of events at Bloomingdale's flagship New York City store, and the Statue of Liberty Centennial in 1986. During this time period, the Board and other similar organizations worked to create an identity for Irish businesses that extended beyond agrarian stereotypes, offering an alternate image of Ireland as a source for luxurious and well-designed products.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Annette Cunningham in May 2013. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.114.
Related Archival Materials
Irish Echo Photographs (AIA 045)
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains photographs, catalogs, brochures, advertisements, printed ephemera, press releases, and newspaper articles concerning the Irish Export Board (Córas Tráchtala) in New York City. The materials document the Board's activities in North America, with specific fashion or home furnishing campaigns revealing the strategies and attempts to create an identity for Irish business that extended beyond agrarian stereotypes. Notable campaigns present in the collection include a series of events at Bloomingdale's flagship New York City store and the Statue of Liberty Centennial in 1986.
Ireland |x Economic policy.; Ireland |x Economic conditions.; Ireland |x Commerce |z United States; Córas Tráchtála
- Annette Sara Cunningham Portfolio, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bloomingdale's Campaign Bags, circa 1977-1986 (Box Shared Tamiment AIAOS001, Folder 7)
- Custom Carpets from Ireland Catalog, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Elegance of Ireland Brochure, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Fashion Editorial Features, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- From Ireland, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Home Furnishings, 1977, circa 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Irish Export Board Plastic Bag, circa 1977-1986 (Box Shared Tamiment AIAOS001, Folder 6)
- Press Releases, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Radio City Music Hall Program, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Treasures of Early Irish Art, 1500 BC to 1500 AD, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)